Reuben Kadish
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Reuben Kadish papers
1851-1995 (bulk 1913-1995)
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Reuben Kadish
7.9 linear feet
This collection, which measures 7.9 linear feet and dates from 1851 to 1995 (bulk 1913-1995), documents the life and career of muralist, sculptor, and educator Reuben Kadish. The papers contain biographical material, letters, personal business records, an exhibition file, notes, writings, artwork, printed material, photographs, and artifacts.
Biographical Note
Reuben Kadish was born in Chicago on January 29, 1913. His father and mother were from Latvia and the Ukraine respectively.
In 1921, the family moved to East Los Angeles, California, where Kadish studied painting under Lorser Feitelson. During this time, he befriended Jackson Pollock and Philip Guston, who attended the Manual Arts High School.
During a trip to New York City in 1930, Kadish was impressed with the modern art, especially the work of the Surrealists, which he saw there. Upon his return to Los Angeles the following year, Kadish attended the Otis Art School, the Stickney School of Art in Pasadena, and Los Angeles City College. He also shared a studio with Philip Guston.
In 1933, Kadish, Guston and Jules Langsner were apprenticed to Mexican muralist, David Alfaro Siqueiros. Their most notable work being the mural “Triumph of Good Over Evil”, at the University of Morelia in Mexico. During the next three years, the three young artists collaborated on painting murals in California and Mexico. After another visit to New York, Kadish was invited to San Francisco by Bill Gaskin to head the art division of the WPA project there, a position he occupied until 1940.
From 1940, Kadish worked as a coppersmith and welder at the Bethlehem Steel Works in San Francisco until 1942, when he joined the Army as a member of the War Artist Unit, serving in India and Southeast Asia during World War II. In 1944, he rejoined his wife Barbara in the Bay Area, but they soon returned to New York City, where Kadish worked for Stanley William Hayter at Atelier 17. In the summer of 1945, the Kadish painted with Jackson Pollock and Lee Krasner in a shared Long Island house on Slow's Point in Amagansett.
In 1946, the Kadishes moved to a dairy farm in Vernon, New Jersey, where they supported themselves by farming until 1957. A catastrophic fire in the studio destroyed most of Kadish's paintings in 1947, causing him to turn his interest to creating sculpture.
After teaching art and design at the Newark School of Fine and Industrial Art in 1957, Kadish taught sculpture at the Brooklyn Museum Art School from 1958-1959. In 1960, he began his thirty-year teaching career at Cooper Union, which ended only a few months before his death on September 20, 1992 in Manhattan.
Scope and Content Note
The Reuben Kadish papers measure 7.9 linear feet and date from 1851 to 1995 with the bulk of the material dating from 1913 to 1995. The collection documents the life and career of muralist, sculptor, and educator Reuben Kadish and contains biographical material, letters, personal business records, an exhibition file, notes, writings, artwork, printed material, photographs, and artifacts.
Biographical material, 1938-1992, includes résumés and personal identification items. Letters are from friends and colleagues including Herman Cherry, Philip Guston, Hilaire Hiler, Jules Langsner, Urban Neininger, Charles Pollock, and Jackson Pollock. One letter from the Leonard Stark family contains a small photograph of Georgia O'Keeffe.
Personal business records, 1952-1995, consist of legal documents, including estate papers for Ida and Reuben Kadish, and financial records. The only specific exhibition file documents the 1990 exhibition Reuben Kadish: Works from 1930 to the Present at the New Jersey State Museum in 1990.
Notes include unbound notes on mural painting, printmaking, sculpture, and other art-related topics, and handwritten translations by William H. Thomson of thirty classic texts by Homer, Horace, and Demosthenes. Writings, 1975-1992, consist of an autobiographical manuscript by Kadish, and typescripts concerning Kadish and other art-related topics by other authors including Dore Ashton, Herman Cherry, Howard Conant, and Judd Tully.
Artwork, undated and 1981-1992, includes a hundred sketches and seventeen watercolors by Kadish, and a drawing for DIG (Archeology) by Barbara Kadish. Printed material relates primarily to exhibitions for Kadish and others but also includes a baseball program autographed by Darryl Strawberry. Photographs include prints of Kadish and other artists working on murals, and photographs picturing family and friends.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into ten series, based on type of material. Although acquired as a gift before the rest of the collection was loaned to the Archives of American Art in 1998, eight photographs are described in Series 9: Photographs, with those included in the 1998 loan.
Each series is arranged chronologically, except Series 2: Letters and Series 6: Writings, which are arranged alphabetically according to the surname of the writer.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1938-1992 (box 1, 2 folders)
Series 2: Letters, 1934-1995, undated (boxes 1-3, 2.5 linear ft.)
Series 3: Personal Business Records, 1952-1995 (boxes 3-4, 37 folders)
Series 4: Exhibition File, 1989-1991 (box 4, 1 folder)
Series 5: Notes, 1851-1853, 1937-1992, undated (boxes 4-5, 35 folders)
Series 6: Writings, 1963-1992, undated (box 5, 14 folders)
Series 7: Artwork, 1981-1992, undated (box 5, sol 10, 8 folders)
Series 8: Printed Material, 1934-1993, undated (boxes 5-7, 67 folders)
Series 9: Photographs, 1913-1992, undated (boxes 7-9, sol 10, 46 folders)
Series 10: Artifacts, undated (box 9, 1 folder)
Related Material
Other resources relating to Reuben Kadish in the Archives of American Art include an oral history interview with Kadish, April 15, 1992.
Appendix: Correspondents from Series 2: Letters
What follows is a complete list of correspondents from Series 2: Letters, which supplements the container list in the finding aid. This list also contains details about the letters sent by each individual listed.
Correspondents Identified by First Name Only
Ab: 1962 (1 postcard)
Alice: 1972-1974 (2 letters)
Barb: undated (1 postcard)
Carleen: 1982 (1 postcard)
Carlotta: 1992 (1 letter to Jenny Lee)
Carol: 1989 (1 letter)
Cathy: undated (1 postcard)
Charley: undated (1 letter)
Clary?: 1995 (1 Christmas card to Jenny Lee)
Clay: 1971 (1 postcard)
Diana: 1971 (1 postcard)
Dolores: 1989 (1 letter)
Doug, Sarah, Molly, and Sam: undated (1 letter)
E., D., and L.: 1990 (1 postcard)
Eddie: 1992 (1 illustrated Christmas card)
Edward: undated (1 postcard)
Ernie: 1980 (1 letter)
Grace?: 1972 (1 postcard)
Honey, Francis, Nick, and Carol: 1995(1 Christmas card to Jenny Lee)
Isabelle: undated (1 letter)
Jeanne: 1987 (2 postcards)
Jeff: undated (1 postcard)
Jeffery: 1979 (1 postcard)
Jennifer: 1987 (1 postcard)
Jim: 1976 (1 letter)
Jin: undated (1 postcard)
Joanna: undated (1 postcard)
Joyce: 1992 (1 postcard)
Kate: 1972 (1 postcard)
Ken and Freida: 1972-1986 (2 letters)
Marina and Bruce: 1987-1989 (1 Christmas card and 2 postcards)
Marion: 1978 (1 postcard)
Martin: 1989-1990 (2 postcards)
Michael: 1985 (1 postcard)
Moira?: 1980 (1 postcard)
Ninette: 1962 (1 postcard)
Patsy: 1985 (1 postcard)
Rene: 1977 (1 postcard)
Roberta: undated (1 postcard)
Robyn: 1988-1989 (2 letters)
Roger and Harriet: undated (1 illustrated postcard)
Ross: 1990 (1 letter)
Sevin?: undated (1 postcard)
Steve: undated and 1994 (4 postcards)
Tom: undated (1 postcard)
Tony: 1978 (1 letter)
Wolfgang: undated (1 postcard)
Correspondents Identified by Surname
Advanced Design: 1989 (1 letter)
Agee, Jon and Carol: undated and 1982-1991 (6 letters, including 2 transparencies and 2 illustrated letters)
Albert, Calvin: 1974 (one postcard with photograph of Albert)
Allan Frumkin Gallery, Inc.: see Frumkin: Allan Frumkin Gallery, Inc.
Allison, Ann: 1964-1976 (2 letters)
American Art and Antiquities: 1978 (1 letter)
American Iris Society: 1988 (1 letter)
American Journal of Archaeology: 1970 (1 letter)
American National Red Cross: 1947 (1 letter)
American Turkish Society: 1973 (1 invitation)
Ames, Arthur: 1938 (1 letter)
AOI Construction, Inc.: 1986 (1 letter)
Archaeological Institute of America, New York Society: 1979 (5 letters)
Archaeometry: 1979 (1 letter)
Archives of American Art: 1976-1991 (5 letters)
Archives of the New York School: 1989 (1 letter)
Art Dealers Association of America, Inc.: 1979 (1 letter)
Art Edifices Enterprises: 1976-1979 (2 letters)
Art for Mexico: 1986 (1 letter)
Art in America: undated (1 letter)
Artists for CORE: 1965 (1 letter)
Artists for SEDF
(Scholarship, Education and Defense Fund for Racial Equality, Inc.): 1967-1968 (3 letters)
Arts Commission of San Francisco: 1988 (1 letter)
Aruz, Joanna: 1972-1986 (4 letters)
Ashford: 1 undated photograph of children
Ashton, Dore and Matti: undated (1 illustrated postcard to Jenny Lee)
Atasoy, Sumer: undated and 1970-1972 (3 letters)
Auerbach, Dorthy: 1989-1990 (2 letters)
Australian National Gallery: see Graham, Lanier
Axe, Martin: undated and 1985-1987 (3 letters)
B., F.: 1964 (1 postcard)
Barger, Illia: 1989 (1 letter including a photograph of an art work)
Barnes Foundation: 1985 (1 letter)
Barnett: David Barnett Gallery: 1971-1973 (4 letters, including a photograph of art work by Kadish)
Barnoya, Miguel Benedict: 1982 (1 letter)
Baskin, David: 1991 (1 letter with illustrated envelope and 6 picture postcards)
Beckmann, Hannes: 1969 (1 letter)
Beeblitz, Patricia: 1972 (1 letter)
Bell, Leland: see Parsons School of Design
Benson, Elaine M.. (Benson Gallery): 1975 (1 letter and 1 postcard)
Berns, Lea: 1964 (1 postcard)
Biddle, George: 1943 (1 telegram)
Bigman, Stephanie: 1963 (1 letter)
Bilimer, Sudiba: 1971 (1 letter)
Binh: Madame Binh Graphics Collective: 1980 (1 letter); see Kadish, Reuben
Blane, Marc: 1978 (1 postcard)
Bloom, Charles L.: 1938 (envelope only)
Blum, Judy: 1967 (1 postcard)
Board of Education, Newark, N.J.: 1957 (1 letter)
Bohen, Barbara: 1973 (1 letter)
Borgenicht: Grace Borgenicht Gallery, Inc.: 1977-1993 (16 letters)
Borgenicht, Lois: see Reim, Johannes
Bourne, Robert B.: 1989-1992 (5 letters)
Braczyk, Robert: 1982-1987 (2 letters containing an exhibition announcement and 2 photographs of art work)
Brandt, Warren: 1973-1981 (1 letter and 1 exhibition announcement)
Braunstein, V.: undated (1 letter)
Briggs, Eta and A.: undated and 1962-1969 (3 letters)
Bromberg, Prof. (State University College, New Paltz, N.Y.): see Kadish, Reuben
Brooklyn Botanic Garden: 1979 (2 letters)
Brooklyn Museum: 1961 (1 letter)
Budnik, Dan: undated and 1989 (1 postcard and 1 exhibition announcement)
Burchfield, Joe and Diana: undated (1 Christmas card)
Burne, Bob: 1985-1986 (2 Christmas cards)
Buto, Gian: undated (1 postcard)
Cadwalader, Stephen: 1984-1991 (5 letters)
Canizaro, James T.: undated and 1966 (2 letters)
Capper's Frames & Prints, Inc.: 1967 (1 letter)
Carlsson Gallery, Inc.: 1966 (1 letter)
Carnegie Institute: 1962 (1 letter)
Carpenter, Scott: undated and 1988-1990 (4 letters)
Carrara, Dominique: 1988 (1 postcard)
Cashen, J. F.: undated (1 letter)
CDS Gallery: 1995 (envelope only; addressed to Jenny Lee)
Century Gallery: see Feitelson
Chang, Songsri: see Wong, Jimmy
Cherry, Herman: 1958-1992 (39 letters); see Writings
Chui, Kam Wah: 1984-1985 (2 Christmas cards)
Click, Ashley: 1988 (1 letter)
Cohn, Susanne: 1986-1991 (3 letters)
Committee of Artists for Greek Relief: 1968 (1 letter)
Constan, Eugene: undated and 1981-1982 (3 postcards); see Kadish, Reuben
Contreras, Belisario: 1976 (2 letters)
Cooper Union: 1962-1991 (19 letters)
Copley, Al L.: 1980-1989 (1 letter and 1 postcard)
CORE (Congress of Racial Equality): 1963 (1 letter)
Corwin, Arthur Hill: 1989 (1 letter)
Crawford: undated (envelope only)
David Barnett Gallery: see Barnett: David Barnett Gallery
Davis, Bruce: 1987 (1 letter)
Davis, Jane: 1960-1989 (5 letters)
Davis, Penny: 1990-1991 (2 letters)
Dehner, Dorothy: undated (2 letters)
Democratic National Committee: undated (envelope only)
Dervish, Melek: 1972 (1 letter from Dervish and a letter to him from Barbara Kadish)
Dillon, Tracey: 1984-1988 (2 postcards)
Dlugoszewski, Lucia: undated (1 letter)
Dolan/Maxwell Gallery: 1988 (memorial for Stanley William Hayter)
Donahue, Jim: 1991 (1 postcard)
Doyon-Bernard, Suzette J.: 1991 (2 letters)
Drummond, L.: 1976 (1 letter)
Duback, Charles: undated (1 letter)
Dugmore, Edward and Eadie: undated and 1959-1992 (18 letters)
Einstein: G. W. Einstein Co., Inc.: 1991-1992 (7 letters)
Elston Fine Arts: 1991 (4 letters)
Elvehjem Art Center: 1975-1977 (2 letters)
Engelman, Martin: 1987 (1 letter)
Erim, Kenan: 1964-1971 (4 letters)
Fanshel, Florence: 1969 (1 letter)
Federal Works Agency: 1938 (1 letter)
Feitelson, R. (Century Gallery): 1934 (1 letter)
Feldman, Florence: 1991 (1 letter)
Feltus, Alan: see Irwin, Lani
Finkelstein, Henry: 1980 (1 letter)
Fishman, N. Michael: 1987-1990 (1 letter and 1 Christmas card)
Flinn, Karen, Tom, and Chris: 1984 (1 Christmas card)
Ford Foundation: 1959 (1 letter)
Fordham University: 1975 (1 letter)
Foundry Unit: 1985 (1 brochure)
Fourcade, Droll, Inc.: 1975 (1 letter)
Fox, George: see Lee, Jenny
Fredericks, Karen: 1981 (1 postcard)
Fribourg Office du Livre (Suisse): 1976 (1 letter)
Friedlander, Angela: 1986 (1 letter)
Friends of Figurative Sculpture: 1988 (1 exhibition announcement)
Frumkin: Allan Frumkin Gallery, Inc.: 1974 (1 letter)
G. W. Einstein Co., Inc.: see Einstein: G. W. Einstein Co., Inc.
Galerie de Seine: 1981 (1 letter)
Galerie Silvia Menzel: see Menzel: Galerie Silvia Menzel
Gallo, Bill: 1988 (autographed scarf illustrated with New York baseball players)
Gardere, Paul and Marcia: undated and 1972-1989 (1 letter and 2 postcards)
Garrett, Zena: 1985-1987 (2 Christmas cards)
Georgia Museum of Art: 1969 (1 letter)
Gerard, C. H. Coster: 1990 (1 letter)
German, Mrs. Ulker: 1970-1972 (3 letters)
Gerstenblith, Patty: 1972-1973 (6 letters)
Gnazzo: see Roecker and Gnazzo
Goerits, Mathias: 1973 (1 letter written on 2 photographs of art work)
Goldberg, Lenore: 1987 (1 postcard)
Goldman, Shifra: see Kadish, Reuben
Gollay & Rosenblatt: 1971-1981 (3 letters)
Gormley, Alice M.: 1982 (1 letter)
Gould, Paul and Lil: 1990 (1 letter, including a photograph of their home and brochures about Florida)
Gouquet-Yurewutz, Claire and Julie: 1970 (1 postcard)
Grace Borgenicht Gallery: see Borgenicht: Grace Borgenicht Gallery
Graham Gallery, Ltd.: 1962-1967 (2 letters)
Graham, Lanier (Australian National Gallery): 1984-1990 (12 letters)
Greenfield-Sanders, Timothy: 1982 (1 postcard)
Greyhound Travel Services, Inc.: 1990 (1 letter)
Guggenheim Gallery: 1986-1987 (5 letters, including a contract, floor-plan, and clippings)
Guggenheim, John: see Kadish, Reuben
Guston, Philip: undated and 1936-1976 (20 letters, including one with an illustration)
Hackman, William: 1989 (1 letter)
Hagel, Hansel and Otto: undated and 1938 (1 letter and 1 photograph of a landscape used as a Christmas card)
Hague, R.: 1969-1975 (2 letters)
Hampton Day School: 1969-1970 (2 letters)
Harris, George: 1947 (1 letter)
Hauptmann, H. (Freie Universitat Berlin): 1973 (1 letter)
Hayter, Stanley William: 1967 (1 letter and 1 illustrated Christmas card) see: Dolan/Maxwell Gallery; see Reddy, Krishna
Haywood, Richard M.: 1966 (1 letter to Prof. Downes)
Heliker, John: undated (1 exhibition announcement)
Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art: see Johnson: Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art
Hesse, Brian: 1970 (1 letter)
Hiler, Hilaire: 1941-1965 (4 letters)
Hios, Theo: 1987 (1 letter)
Hirsh, Hy: 1960 (1 letter)
Holloway: Jan Holloway Gallery: 1987 (1 letter)
Hong Ying Restaurant: 1989 (1 letter)
Houstoun, Pud: 1983-1986 (1 letter, including a resume and photograph of family, and 1 postcard)
Hunterdon Art Center: 1981 (1 letter)
Hurlburt, Larry: 1978-1980 (1 letter and 1 postcard) see Mexican Muralists in the United States
Ilya Schor Foundation, Inc.: see Schor: Ilya Schor Foundation, Inc.
Independent Curators, Inc.: 1988-[1990] (2 letters)
Ironmite Corporation: see Lee, Jenny
Irwin, Lani, and Alan Feltus: 1974-1986 (3 letters)
Istituto Nazionale per la Grafica: 1988-1990 (5 letters, including one in Spanish)
Jackman: undated (envelope only)
Jamaica Center: 1975 (2 letters)
Jan Holloway Gallery: see Holloway: Jan Holloway Gallery
Johnson, Daniel LaRue: 1991 (1 letter)
Johnson: Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art: 1987 (5 letters)
Johnson, Una E.: 1978 (1 letter)
Jorgensen, Henry and Elizabeth: 1964-1985 (6 family photograph Christmas cards)
Judah L. Magnes Museum: see Magnes: Judah L. Magnes Museum
Kadish, Barbara: undated and 1963-1974 (19 letters to Hilda O'Connell)
Kadish, Dan: 1964-1973 (6 letters, including one with illustrations, and 3 photographs of art work)
Kadish, David: 1990 (1 letter)
Kadish, Frank and Lorain: 1983-1991 (6 letters)
Kadish, Jonathan: 1970-1973 (3 letters)
Kadish, Julian: 1970 (1 letter)
Kadish, Kennan: 1970-1990 (4 letters, including one to Jenny Lee)
Kadish, Morris [Moishe] and Ruth: 1973-1998 (28 letters); see Kadish, Reuben
Kadish, Philip: undated and 1990 (1 letter and 1 postcard)
Kadish, Reuben, to Binh: Madame Binh Graphics Collective: 1982 (1 letter)
Kadish, Reuben, to Bromberg, Prof. (State University College, New Paltz, N.Y.): 1968 (1 letter)
Kadish, Reuben, to Constan, Eugene: undated (1 letter)
Kadish, Reuben, to Goldman, Shifra: undated (1 letter)
Kadish, Reuben, to Guggenheim, John: 1986-1987 (3 letters)
Kadish, Reuben, to Kadish family: 1990 (1 letter)
Kadish, Reuben, to Kadish, Ruth and Moishe: 1984 (1 letter)
Kadish, Reuben, to Kyle, Mr.: 1967 (2 letters)
Kadish, Reuben, to Lee, Jenny: 1987-1992 (66 letters)
Kadish, Reuben, to Mayer, Musa (Ingie): [1988] (1 letter)
Kadish, Reuben, to Mitchel, Julio: 1988 (1 postcard)
Kadish, Reuben, to Page, Lee: 1981 (1 letter)
Kadish, Reuben, to Pound, Brandy: undated (2 letters)
Kadish, Reuben, to Reed, Susan: 1992 (1 letter)
Kadish, Reuben, to Rodriguez family: undated and 1989 (2 letters)
Kadish, Reuben, to Spring, Bob: 1992 (1 letter)
Kaufman, B. John: undated (5 photographs of art work)
Kean College of New Jersey: 1981 (1 letter)
Kenkeleba House, Inc.: 1987 (2 letters and an exhibition announcement)
Kettenbach, Friedel: 1985 (1 Christmas card)
Klayman, Toby Judith: 1981 (1 letter)
Klinger, Randy: 1988 (1 letter)
Kohn, Gabe: 1959-1962 (6 letters)
Krafft, Jo: undated (1 letter)
Kroeplin, Jim: 1974 (1 letter)
Kupferman, Lawrence: 1943-1944 (6 letters)
Kyle, Thomas: see Kadish, Reuben; see Museum of Contemporary Crafts
L., Howard: 1980 (1 letter)
Lacy, Bill: see Lee, Jenny
Landmark Gallery, Inc.: 1977-1978 (2 letters)
Langsner, Jules: undated and 1937-1963 (36 letters, including a photograph of a railroad yard, and 9 photographs of Delhi, India)
Lebt?, Bill: 1967 (1 letter)
Lee, Jenny: undated and 1985-1992 (61 letters, including clippings, exhibition announcements, 2 books Dreams: Visions of the Night by David Coxhead and Susan Hiller, and Italian Renaissance Sculpture by John Pope-Hennessy, and 8 photographs of the Watts Towers; 7 letters are illustrated); see Kadish, Reuben. Letters to: Fox, George: 1987 (1 letter); Lacy, Bill: 1987 (1 letter); McNamara, Mary: 1987 (1 letter); Miller, Lee Ann (Cooper Union): 1987 (1 letter)
Leggist?, Gihuan: 1937 (1 letter)
Lehman: Herbert H. Lehman College: 1976 (1 letter)
Leong, Jim: 1990 (1 letter, including a resume)
Lesher, Derek: 1992 (1 letter)
Levine, Marsha: undated and 1973-1986 (12 letters)
Life magazine: 1944-1960 (2 letters)
Lightfoot, Cathy: 1981 (1 exhibition announcement)
Littlefield, William H.: 1969 (1 letter)
Los Angeles Sanatorium and Expatients Home: 1936 (1 letter)
Lukela?, Bob: 1962 (1 postcard)
Lynch, Bill: undated and 1991 (6 postcards and 1 letter, all illustrated)
Madame Binh Graphics Collective: see Binh: Madame Binh Graphics Collective
Magnes: Judah L. Magnes Museum: undated (1 letter)
Magnus, Rhonda: 1990 (1 illustrated letter)
Mallary, R.: 1938 (1 letter)
Mandel, Johanna and Aaron: 1974-1991 (3 letters, including a photograph of children)
Manhattanville College: 1969-1971 (3 letters)
Manning: undated (1 Christmas card)
Marciano, Shirley: 1964-1970 (6 letters)
Marcus, Joel: 1977 (1 letter)
Marrero, Onelio: 1988 (1 letter)
Marsh, Catherine: 1990 (1 letter)
Martin, Fletcher: 1937-1979 (4 letters, including one illustration)
Masini, Donna, and William Pitt Root: 1987-1991 (3 letters, including a decorated frame and photograph)
Mason, William and Melanie: 1984
Matisse, Henri: 1948 (photocopy of letter from Matisse to Mr. Clifford)
Matlin, David and Gail: 1981-1990 (2 letters)
Mayer, Musa (Ingie): 1987-1989 (5 letters); see Kadish, Reuben
McCoy, Sande (nee Pollock): undated and 1935-1986 (6 letters)
McDermott, Paul M.: 1972 (1 letter)
McFadden, Elizabeth: 1984 (1 letter)
McGowan, Mary Beth: 1988 (1 letter)
McH.: undated (1 letter to E. E. L.)
McHale, Rachel: 1990 (1 Christmas card and 1 postcard)
McLaughlin, Janie: 1967-1968 (3 letters and 1 postcard)
McNamara, Mary: see Lee, Jenny
Meert, Joseph: see Potter, Jeffrey
Menil Collection: 1989 (1 letter)
Menzel: Galerie Silvia Menzel: 1987 (2 exhibition catalogs)
Metropolitan Museum of Art: 1975- 1986 (2 letters)
Mexican Muralists in the United States: Their Work and Influence (NEH research project): 1980-1982 (7 letters)
Michigan State University: 1966 (1 letter)
Millburn Corporation: 1988 (1 announcement for New York Aegean Bronze Age Colloquium)
Miller, Lee Ann (Cooper Union): see Lee, Jenny
Mills, J. D.: 1984-1986 (3 Christmas cards)
Ministero per i Beni Culturali e Ambientali: 1989 (2 letters in Spanish)
Minneapolis Institute of Arts: 1959 (2 letters)
Mirski, Boris: 1945 (1 letter)
Mitchel, Julio: see Kadish, Reuben
Montgomery family: 1973-1986 (14 letters, including 19 photographs of family members and sculpture)
Moore, Lucile and Jim Al: 1985-1986 (2 Christmas cards)
Morgan, Dane D.: 1963 (1 letter)
Moss, Tobey C.: 1986 (1 letter)
Museu de Arte Moderna de Sao Paulo: 1959 (1 letter)
Museum of Contemporary Crafts: 1967 (1 letter)
Museum of Modern Art: 1963 (1 letter)
Mythic Arts Africa: 1987 (1 letter from Jenny Lee)
National Academy of Design: undated (1 letter)
National Gallery of Art: 1975 (1 letter)
National Geographic Society: undated (1 form letter)
National Museum of American Art: 1986-1990 (7 letters)
National Social Welfare Assembly, Inc.: 1967 (1 letter)
NBC News: undated (1 letter)
Neininger, Urban and Jean: undated and 1937-1989 (28 letters)
Nemanic, Todd: 1981 (1 exhibition announcement)
Newark Museum: 1968 (1 letter)
Newark Public School of Fine and Industrial Art: undated and 1956-1960 (4 letters)
Newbill, Al: 1976-1987 (4 letters)
New Jersey State Council on the Arts: 1989 (1 letter)
New Jersey State Museum: 1976-1991 (10 letters)
New York Civil Liberties Union: 1972 (1 postcard)
New York Studio School: 1971-1977 (5 letters)
New York University: 1963 (1 letter)
North Jersey Cultural Council: 1970-1974 (2 letters)
O'Connell, Hilda: undated and 1963-1990 (18 letters); see Kadish, Barbara
Odate, Gerlinde: 1966-1974 (2 letters, including one with an illustration)
O'Keeffe, Georgia: see Stark, Leonard
Oles, James: 1991 (1 postcard)
Oord, A. and B.: 1984 (1 postcard)
Oregon: University of Oregon: 1973-1976 (4 letters)
Pace, Stephen: 1976-1987 (1 letter and an exhibition announcement)
Page, Lee: see Kadish, Reuben
Panero, Lorenza (Laurie): 1989-1991 (1 letter enclosing a typescript “The Three Masters of Mexican Muralism and Their Impact on the Development of American Art”, and 1 exhibition announcement in Spanish)
Parsons School of Design: 1991 (1 announcement for memorial for Leland Bell)
Pekarsky, Mel: 1992 (7 letters)
Perrone, Francis S., M.D.: 1972 (1 invoice)
Phillips, Bill and Helen: 1947-1981 (2 letters and a press release)
Pollock: see McCoy, Sande